# **David Gallo**

David.Gallo747@gmail.com | +33 6 52 65 36 28 | Linkedin.com/in/DavidGallo747

## **SUMMARY**

High-achieving trilingual MSc candidate at the Toulouse Business School, with consulting, data analytics, entrepreneurship, volunteering, and leadership experience. Graduated Summa Cum Laude from the University of Ottawa, after completing an Honours Bachelors of Commerce (Business Technology Management).

## **HIGHLIGHTS**

- 9.1 CGPA (10-point scale), Dean's List
- Cybersecurity data analytics experience
- Excellent interpersonal/communication skills
- Leadership in extracurriculars

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Deloitte Digital**

May 2018 - Sep. 2018; Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019; Jan. 2021 - Present

Business Technology Analyst – Technology Consulting

- Led the QA team for a large-scale technology implementation with the federal government to overhaul a citizen-facing intake process that receives hundreds of thousands of annual applications. As QA Lead, I was directly responsible for the management of testing, automation, deployments, and project governance.
- Developed and implemented a benchmarking framework for a public utility company looking to overhaul its internal IM services and supporting technologies.
- Identified and analyzed business requirements for a cloud-based ERP implementation through workshops and independent research, then conducted a vendor market assessment.
- Created an IM framework + roadmap and developed a target operating model for a complete service delivery overhaul of a federal public sector department.

# **Canadian Internet Registration Authority (CIRA)**

May 2020 – Dec 2020

Cybersecurity Product Data Analyst

- Prototyped DNS firewall features in an agile environment using a scrum framework.
- Developed machine learning workflow using ElasticSearch (NoSQL database), MySQL, and Python to process DNS data in real-time and prepare it for data analysis.
- Implemented unsupervised machine learning techniques including hierarchical and density-based clustering to analyze millions of daily DNS requests and isolate malicious devices.
- Deployed the solution in an integrated Amazon AWS ecosystem, with scalable EC2 instances.
- Created an API-driven dashboard to enable data-driven decision-making for marketing.

## **Department of National Defence**

Jan. 2020 - May 2020

Accommodations Database Administrator

- Developed a comprehensive project plan to migrate business assets to MS SharePoint.
- Developed a SharePoint-hosted SQL database to manage all accommodations tracking.

# **Department of Fisheries and Oceans**

May 2019 – Aug. 2019

Correspondence Officer, Legal Services

- Overhauled an integral SQL-based database to improve daily managerial operations.
- Managed time-critical requests for legal input by the Assistant Deputy Minister.

**MNP LLP** Jan. 2019 – May 2019

*Analyst/Developer – Technology Consulting* 

- Performed in-depth research to compare leading DXP solutions and their application in various industries. Identified new client opportunities.
- Developed a comprehensive training curriculum for province-wide Tableau training
- Assessed current state IM practices of a public sector organization and defined the future state for a records management system, as well as a fit-gap analysis for native MS Sharepoint capabilities.
- Acted as the sole content driver of two key proposals for business technology implementations.

# **Department of National Defence**

Apr. 2017 – May 2018; Sep. 2018 – Dec. 2018

Records Management

- Managed the accessibility and security of vast amounts of data using OpenText solutions.
- Improved workplace efficiency by developing new methods to objectify client business requirements and scripted custom automation tools, leading to improved client interactions.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Toulouse Business School**

Aug. 2021 – Present

Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence and Business Analytics

# **University of Ottawa**

Sep. 2016 – Jun. 2021

Honours Bachelor of Commerce (Business Technology Management) (Co-op) (French Immersion) Summa Cum Laude

- 9.1 CGPA (10-point scale). Dean's Honour List.
- Selected for and completed the intensive two-year Profession of Management Consulting Program, to solve and present real business cases with leading consulting firms on a weekly basis.
- Selected for and completed the four-year International Certificate Program (Honours).

**Bell High School** Sep. 2012 – Jun. 2016

Ontario Secondary School Diploma. Gifted. French Immersion.

• 9.0 CGPA (10-point scale). Silver Medalist, Honour Roll.

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Fluent in English/Italian/French (DELF Level B2 and uOttawa French Immersion Certificate).
- Received awards including:
  - o Accenture Scholarship Fund (2020)
  - o University of Ottawa Merit Scholarship (2016-2020)
  - o JDC MIS 2<sup>nd</sup> Place (2019), JDC VIP Academic (2018-2019)
  - o Lazaridis International Case Conference 3<sup>rd</sup> Place (2018)
  - o AP Scholar Award (2016)
  - o Craig Cameron Memorial Scholarship (2016)
  - o Computer and IS Award (2015)
  - o Broadview Musicianship Award (2012)
  - o OPC Award for Student Leadership (2011)

#### **LEADERSHIP**

- Elected three times to the University of Ottawa Senate and Telfer Faculty Council (2018 to 2020).
  - o These are the two highest academic governance bodies of the university and faculty, comprised of faculty representatives, Deans, Directors, VPs, and the Chancellor/President.
  - o Provided input in all academic regulations, policies, and programs for the University.
- Musical Director for the CASCO Foundation to plan/perform a fundraising charity show raising money for the Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario (CHEO).
- Director of Sponsorship of the Telfer Human Resources Association.
  - Created a compelling sponsorship package and pitched the association to various local firms to garner support and sponsorship.
  - o Managed the leading source of revenue to finance the association.
- Vice President (Internal Affairs) of the Telfer Human Resources Association.
  - Oversaw all planning and relations with the University and its students, including strategies to recruit new members and grow the alumni network.
  - Overhauled member recruitment strategies and implemented a new case management system.
- Sought a leading role in many other extra-curricular activities and case competitions, including:
  - o 2-time Academic VIP and 2019 Finalist at Jeux Du Commerce (the largest Eastern Canadian business case competition); selected for the MIS team. Weekly 4-hour case cracks.
  - o Coach for the 2019, 2020, and 2021 JDC and JDCC MIS teams.
  - o 3<sup>rd</sup>-place at the Lazaridis International Case Competition.

## INTERESTS AND VOLUNTEERING

- Experienced with: Python, C, Elastic Stack, VBA, MySQL, Jet SQL, MS Jscript, MS Office, Tableau, Dynamics 365, SharePoint, OpenText Content Suite, Klipfolio, Jira, and Confluence.
- Volunteered regularly with the CASCO Foundation to support CHEO as a musician, helping raise \$250,000 CAD over three years, involving full-day weekly rehearsals from September to December.
- Founded the rock band AVRA; coordinated with industry professionals to perform at events including Ottawa's largest music festival (RBC Bluesfest), and to release music on the radio (Live 88.5).
- Completed Grade 8 Piano with the Royal Conservatory of Music after 14 years, practiced and performed drums for the last 9 years.